Gabriel Diegel

Email: gabriel.diegel@icloud.com Github: https://github.com/gdiegel

Professional Summary

Creative Software Engineer with 15 years of demonstrated experience in Software Engineering, Solutions Architecture, and Technology Leadership. Deep expertise in Distributed Systems, Microservices, Event-Driven Architecture, and Continuous Delivery. Highly motivated self-starter with a winning mindset and a bias for action.

Currently

Senior Software Engineer at LeagueApps in New York, US

Programming languages

Java, Go, Kotlin, Python

Technologies

Spring Boot, WebFlux, Quarkus, Echo, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Pub/Sub, Maven, Gradle, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Terraform, Datadog

Experience

| 2023-current | Senior Software Engineer at LeagueApps in New York, New York, US |
|--------------|--|
| 2019-2022 | Senior Software Engineer at Tekton in Lima, Peru |
| 2018-2019 | Senior Software Development Engineer in Test at 1&1 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany |
| 2013-2018 | Test Software Development Engineer in Test at 1&1 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany |
| 2010-2012 | Analyst at Atos Worldline GmbH in Frankfurt, Germany |
| 2009-2010 | Software Engineer at Fraunhofer Institute for Physical Measurement Techniques IPM in Freiburg, Germany |

Education

B.Sc. in Psychology at Universität Hagen, Germany
Dipl.-Ing. (FH) in Electrical Engineering at Hochschule Karlsruhe, Germany

Thesis: "Development of an automated image analysis software for a fluorescence-based data acquisition system for the detection of airborne microorganisms"

Projects

2016 retryJ: A retry library for Java

Languages

German: Native, English: Fluent, Spanish: Fluent, Italian: Learning

Articles

| 2015 | "Take your testing DSL to the next level with custom assertions" |
|------|--|
| 2016 | "JUnit5-Feeble screams from forests well known" |
| 2017 | "Using neo-problem with a pure Spring Boot service" |
| 2018 | "Writing a custom test engine with Kotlin" |
| 2019 | "Automated acceptance testing" |
| 2019 | "Running acceptance tests on GitlabCI" |